Swapnil Mishra

CONTACT INFORMATION

Imperial College London School of Public Health Norfolk Place, St Mary's Campus Paddington, London W2 1PG, AUS

Phone: +44 (0)20 7594 9222 E-mail: s.mishra@imperial.ac.uk WWW: https://s-mishra.github.io/

RESEARCH INTERESTS Modeling and Predicting evolution of popularity on social media: epidemiology, geo-statistics, online networks, stochastic processes, machine learning, time-series prediction.

EDUCATION

The Australian National University, Canberra, AUS

Ph.D., Research School of Computer Science, 2015-2019

- Thesis: Linking Models for Collective Attention in Social Media
- Advisors: Dr. Lexing Xie and Dr. Marian-Andrei Rizoiu

Master of Computing (First class Hons.), Research School of Computer Science, 2012-2012

- Topic: Implementation and Experiments with Novel Parallel and Bursty Non-parametric Topic Models
- Advisor: Professor Wray Buntine

Maharashtra Institute of Technology, Pune, India

B.E, Computer Engineering, 2005-2009

• Prof.Savita Kulkarni

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Swapnil Mishra "Bridging Models for Popularity Prediction on Social Media." In ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM '19), Melbourne, AUS, 2019.
- [2] **S Mishra**, MA Rizoiu, L Xie "Modeling Popularity in Asynchronous Social Media Streams with Recurrent Networks." *In International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media (ICWSM '18), Stanford, CA, USA, 2018.*
- [3] MA Rizoiu, **S Mishra**, Q Kong, M Carman, L Xie "SIR-Hawkes: on the Relationship Between Epidemic Models and Hawkes Point Processes." *Proceedings of the 27th International Conference on World Wide Web 2018, WWW'18, Lyon.*
- [4] MA Rizoiu, Y Lee, **S Mishra**, L Xie "A Tutorial on Hawkes Processes for Events in Social Media." *Book Chapter, Research Frontier of Multimedia, Morgan & Claypool.*
- [5] **S Mishra**, MA Rizoiu, L Xie "Feature driven and point process approaches for popularity prediction." *Proceedings of the 25th ACM International on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM'16, Indianapolis.*
- [6] W Buntine., S Mishra. "Experiments with non-parametric topic models." *Proceedings* of the 20th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining, KDD'14, NY.
- [7] W Buntine., S Mishra. "Developing Topic Models for Information Retrieval." NIPS 2013 Topic modelling workshop, Lake Tahoe, Nevada US.

AWARDS

ICWSM Student Travel Award (2018)

ANU Vice Chancellor Travel Grant (2018)

CIKM Student Travel Grant (2016) KDD Student Travel Grant (2014)

ABU Robocon Misumi Sponsors Award

ABU Robocon Mabuchi Motor Award

WORK EXPERIENCE Research Assistant

Research Assistant Feb 2015 to present

Research School of Computer Science, Australian National University Supervisor:Dr. Lexing Xie

Research Assistant Jul 2014 to Nov 2014

Optimisation Research Group,

NICTA(Data61)

Supervisors: Dr. Lexing Xie

Research Assistant Nov 2012 to Jun 2014

Machine Learning Research Group, Australian National University Supervisors: Prof. Wray Buntine

System Engineer Jul 2009 to Jul 2011

Decision Science, Infosys Ltd, Bangalore Client: Bank of America

TEACHING EXPERIENCE Co-Lecturer, 2018.7-2018.11, 2017.7-2017.11

Australian National University, Canberra, AUS,

Introduction to Programming for Data Scientists, COMP2420/6420, Semester 2.

Co-Developer and Co-Lecturer, 2018.2-2018.7

Australian National University, Canberra, AUS,

Introduction to Data Management, Analysis and Security, COMP2420/6420, Semester 1.

Teaching Assistant, 2017.7-2017.11, 2016.7-2016.11, 2014.7-2014.11, 2013.7-2013.11

Australian National University, Canberra, AUS, Document Analysis, COMP4650/6490, Semester 2.

REFERENCES

Dr. Lexing Xie

Associate Professor Phone: +61 (0)2 6125 1646 Research School of Computer Science E-mail: lexing.xlx@anu.edu.au

The Australian National University

Dr. Marian-Andrei Rizoiu

Research Fellow Phone: +61 (0)2 6125 8605 Research School of Computer Science *E-mail*: marian-andrei.rizoiu@anu.edu.au

The Australian National University

Professor Wray Buntine

Professor Phone: +61 420813031 Clayton School of Information Technology *E-mail*: wray.buntine@monash.edu

Monash University